(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.1",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
はい、どうもー
Hi, everyone!
ねー
Hey.
むぎゅっ
*Squeeze*
ねこ...
Neko...
だからそれでいいのよね
So that's fine, isn't it?
だからね
That's why...
そうなんだね
I see.
んやだ
No way.
せやな
That's true.
いいなー
That's nice.
まあまあかなー
It's okay, I guess.
ねー
Right?
えー
Eh?
ねっ
Right?
すごー
Amazing.
えらい！
Good job!
あれはさー
You know that...
それが一番いいのでは？
Isn't that the best?
んまあ 絶対なるよほうだい
Well, it'll definitely be all-you-can-...
ねっ もう
Right? Already...
べそべそ
Besobeso (sobbing sound)
んねっ 急げー
Yeah, hurry up!
そうそう
That's right.
くる？
Coming?
もー
Jeez...
怖くないよ 出ておいで
It's not scary, come on out.
とっても幸せなことだね
That's a very happy thing, isn't it?
みんなのコメント見るの大好きだから僕
Because I love looking at everyone's comments.
いくぞー！
Here we go!
にゃー 助けてー
Nya! Help me!
あると思う
I think it's there.
うんとー
Hmm...
みんな好きだけどね
I like everyone, though.
わ！それはやばい
Wah! That's bad.
ラッキー
Lucky!
えー これね これね
Eh, this, right? This.
しょうがないよね
Can't be helped, right?
んにゃー
Nnya...
んにゃーよ
はーっ ほい
Ha! There.
んにゃー
Nnya!
おりゃー
Oryaa!
んにゃー
Nnya!
僕のせいじゃないよ
It's not my fault.
おい 知らね
Hey, I don't know.
だめだめ
No, no.
おー
Oh.
なんでー
Why?
ねこまんざい
Neko-manzai.
すごいすごい
Amazing, amazing.
お邪魔します
Excuse me for entering.
うわ！うー！
Woah! Uu!
おももぐ おかゆ
Omomogu Okayu.
ここはある田舎のおにぎり屋さん
This is an onigiri shop in the countryside.
そこにはゲームが大好きなおばあちゃんと...
There lives a grandmother who loves games and...
猫が住んでいました。
...a cat.
すっかり影響を受けてゲーマーのようです。
She's been completely influenced and seems to be a gamer now.
ある日この村にクマの着ぐるみがチラシを配りに来ていました。
One day, someone in a bear costume came to the village to hand out flyers.
内容は、アイドルオーディション開催中！という内容でした。
The content was about an idol audition being held!
この猫はゲームばっかりしてたので、自分にはちょっと難しいかも...と思いました。
This cat did nothing but play games, so she thought it might be a bit difficult for her.
ーあっ
ーAh!
これだったら...ちょっとやってみたいかも...
If it's this... I might want to try it a bit...
でもお店のこともあるしな...
But there's also the shop to consider...
とりあえずオーディション受けてみたら？
Why don't you just try the audition for now?
誰でもできることじゃないんだし...
It's not something just anyone can do...
なにより、やってみたいんでしょう？そんな顔してるわよ。
More than anything, you want to try it, right? You have that look on your face.
あんた、昔からゲームも好きだったけど
You've always loved games, but...
人を笑顔にすることが大好きだったじゃないー
You also loved making people smile, didn't you?
アイドルか...
An idol, huh...
僕がホロライブに入ったらどんな風になってるんだろう？
If I joined Hololive, what would I be like?
今はまだ想像できないや...
I can't even imagine it yet...
ネコカブリーナ
作詞・作曲・編曲：ピノキオピー
Nekokaburina
Lyrics/Music/Arrangement: PinocchioP
生の本音はエグいから
Raw true feelings are harsh
ちゃんと火を通して食べてね
So make sure to cook them before eating
（もぐもぐ）
(Munch munch)
リップサービスはズルいかな？
Is lip service cheating?
それも以心伝心のレシピ
That's also a heart-to-heart recipe
みんなー 自分 偽ってるかい？
Everyone, are you faking it?
嘘の万国博覧会
A world expo of lies
みんなー 自分 偽ってるかい？
Everyone, are you faking it?
（いえす！）
(Yes!)
痛みを飼いならして
Tame the pain
シャー！
Shaa!
嫌いだけど「スキ」
I hate it, but I "like" it
不味くても「オイシイ」
Even if it tastes bad, it's "delicious"
着ぐるみを脱ぎハグしてあげる
I'll take off the costume and give you a hug
（らびんゆー）
(Lovin' you)
泣かせないように
So I don't make you cry
怒らせないように
So I don't make you angry
丁度良く君と遊びたいのだ
I want to play with you just right
ネコカブリーナ ネコカブリーナ
Nekokaburina, Nekokaburina
ちょっと臆病な君が好き
I like you when you're a bit timid
ネコカブリーナ ネコカブリーナ
Nekokaburina, Nekokaburina
取り繕ってる僕が好き？
Do you like me when I'm putting on a front?
弱さを知ってる 君が好きだよ
I like you, who knows weakness
「思う」と「言う」とでは大違い
There's a big difference between "thinking" and "saying"
建前も用法と用量次第
Social facades also depend on usage and dosage
みんな〜 自分 踊ってるかい？
Everyone, are you dancing with yourselves?
ひとりぼっちの音楽隊
A one-person marching band
みんな〜 自分 踊ってるかい？
Everyone, are you dancing with yourselves?
首輪の鈴鳴らして
Ring the bell on your collar
フギャー
Fugyaa!
災難だけど「ハッピー」
It's a disaster, but I'm 'happy'
しんどくても「ヘイキ」
It's tough, but I'm 'okay'
アベコベな夢を見せてあげる
I'll show you an inside-out dream
傷つけないように 追い詰めないように
So as not to hurt, so as not to corner you
夜明けまで君とふざけあうのだ
I'll fool around with you until dawn
ネコカブリーナ ネコカブリーナ
Neko Kaburina, Neko Kaburina
(にゃー)
(Nya)
爪を丸めてる君が好き
I like you when you tuck your claws in
ネコカブリーナ ネコカブリーナ
Neko Kaburina, Neko Kaburina
涙を見せない 僕が好き？
Do you like me when I don't show tears?
痛みを知ってる 君が好きだよ
I like you who knows what pain is
君は猫 猫 ファスナーつきの猫
You're a cat, a cat, a cat with a zipper
君は人 人 ファスナーつきの人
You're a person, a person, a person with a zipper
あれは UFO UFO ファスナーつきの UFO
That's a UFO, a UFO, a UFO with a zipper
君は猫 猫 ファスナーつきの
You're a cat, a cat, with a zipper
君は人 人 ファスナーつきの
You're a person, a person, with a zipper
あれは UFO UFO ファスナーつきの
That's a UFO, a UFO, with a zipper
君は誰 誰 特別な人
Who are you? Who are you? A special person
ネコカブリーナ ネコカブリーナ (にゃー)
Neko Kaburina, Neko Kaburina (Nya)
ちょっと臆病な君が好き
I like you when you're a bit cowardly
君も僕も馴染めない世界で
In a world where neither you nor I fit in
やっと見つけた居場所だから
Because it's a place we finally found
ネコカブリーナ ネコカブリーナ
Neko Kaburina, Neko Kaburina
取り繕ってる僕が好き？
Do you like me when I'm putting on an act?
君も僕もどうかしてる世界で
In a world where both you and I are crazy
明日もまた会えたら良いな
I hope we can meet again tomorrow
ネコカブリーナ ネコカブリーナ (にゃー)
Neko Kaburina, Neko Kaburina (Nya)
弱さを知ってる 君が好きだよ
I like you who knows what weakness is
もしもし〜！ ころさん？
Hello? Koro-san?
ごめんね仕事終わりに
Sorry to call right after you finished work.
おかゆ〜！ うん全然大丈夫だよ！
Okayu! Yeah, it's totally fine!
嬉しいなおかゆからの電話...
I'm so happy to get a call from Okayu...
えへへ...
Ehehe...
ころさん ホロライブって知ってる？
Koro-san, do you know about Hololive?
名前くらいは知ってるけどー... どうしたの？
I know the name, but... what's up?
う〜ん.........
Hmm.........
僕と一緒にデビューしてみない？
Would you like to debut with me?
え〜！ なになにどういうことどういうこと！？
Eh! Wait, what? What do you mean by that!?
でも おかゆとだったらいいかもー！
But if it's with Okayu, it might be good!
うん！
Yeah!
ほんと！
Really!
よ〜し！ そうと決まれば...
Alright! Since that's settled...
善は急げだあああ！
Strike while the iron is hot!
ねえ、まだまだ？ 急いで！
Hey, not yet? Hurry up!
出かける準備はできたかい？
Are you ready to go out?
キミに見せたい 不思議の世界
I want to show you a world of wonder
見送りならいらない
I don't need a send-off
たとえ火の中 水の中
Even in fire or in water
手さぐりで 見えない 今日のなか
Fumbling through an invisible today
1秒先だって まだ知らないけど
I don't even know what's one second ahead
いつも思い出はどれも
All the memories, every single one
全部 ボールの中に
Are all inside the ball
1・2・3 で飛び込め！
Jump in on 1, 2, 3!
いつか描いた未来が
The future I once imagined
ボクの ポケットにあるから
Is right here in my pocket
はじめましては いつだって初めてさ
A first meeting is always the first time
ためらうことなどない
There's no need to hesitate
（トライ！ トライ！ レッツ ハブ ア ファイト！）
(Try! Try! Let's have a fight!)
1 バトルをしたなら
1, if we have a battle
2 笑うか泣いたって
2, whether we laugh or cry
3 で仲間になろうよ
3, let's become companions
あの日だって この日だって いつだってそうしていた
That day, this day, we've always done that
先も見えない 果ても知らない
Can't see ahead, don't know the end
世界がそこにあるけど レッツゴー！
But the world is right there, let's go!
転んで すりむいて
Falling down and skinning my knees
何度も歩き出す隣
I'll keep walking by your side
キミに決めた！
I choose you!
隣の街から 景色は
The scenery from the next town over
ため息つくほど世界は
The world makes me sigh so much
めまぐるしく まわり変わる
It's spinning and changing dizzily
ボクを置き去りにする
Leaving me behind
子供の頃には 夢中で
When I was a child, I was so absorbed
くぐり抜けた 穴ぼこでも
Even through the holes I scrambled through
しばらくぶりだな 見落としていたの？
It's been a while, did I overlook it?
でもね忘れた景色も
But you know, even the forgotten scenery
今日の
In today's...
どこかにあるよ
...somewhere out there.
1・2・3で飛び出せ！
Jump out on 1, 2, 3!
散々だって泣いていた
Even those days of endless crying,
日々とボールの外まで
let's send them beyond the Poké Ball.
「どこへ行こうか？」は
Asking "Where shall we go?"
「どこへだって行ける」でしょ？
means "We can go anywhere," right?
息つく暇など
There's no time to rest...
ナイ！
Nope!
トライ！
Try!
Why don't we go?
1 言葉を超えて
1, Beyond words,
2 境界線の先の
2, past the boundaries,
まだ見ぬ君まで
until we reach the you we haven't seen.
倒れるなら手を突くなら
If I fall, if I must brace myself,
前だって決めたんだ
I've decided it'll be moving forward.
日が沈むように影伸びて
Like the setting sun lengthening shadows,
背丈も変わっているけど
our height has changed too.
レッツゴー
Let's go!
雨上がりでなくちゃ
It has to be after the rain...
レッツゴー
Let's go!
晴れ間に虹はない
...there's no rainbow in a sunny sky.
あの日から気づいている
I've known that since that day.
君は君はいつの間やら
You, you, before I knew it...
大人になっちゃいないかい？
...haven't you grown up?
埃を被ったボロ着の
In the dusty rags,
右ぽっけに置いてきた
in the right pocket I left behind,
片手に収まる冒険
an adventure that fits in one hand.
ボクラの全てだった
It was our everything.
あの頃の思い出が
Those memories from back then
君を探しているよ
are searching for you.
1・2・3で飛び込め！
Dive in on 1, 2, 3!
いつか描いた未来が
The future I once drew
ボクのポケットにあるから
is right here in my pocket.
どこかへ行こうよ
Let's go somewhere.
どこへだって連れてってよ
Take me anywhere.
ためらうことなど
Hesitating is...
ナイ！
Nope!
トライ！
Try!
Let's have a fight!
1 バトルをしたなら
1, Once we battle,
2 笑うか泣いたって
2, whether laughing or crying,
3 で仲間になろうよ
3, let's become friends.
あの日だってこの日だって
On that day, on this day,
いつだってそうしていた
we always did just that.
先も見えない果ても知らない
I don't know the future or the end,
世界がそこにあるけど
but the world is right there.
レッツゴー
Let's go!
転んですりむいて
Tumbling and grazing our knees,
レッツゴー
Let's go!
何度も歩き出す隣
stepping forward again by your side,
キミにきめた！
I choose you!
おかゆ〜！このレトロゲー一緒にやらね〜？
Okayu! Want to play this retro game together?
お〜、めっちゃ名作RPGじゃん〜〜
Oh, it's a total classic RPG!
これ楽しそうだね
This looks like fun.
めっちゃ難しかったけど…ラスボスやっと倒せそう！
It was super hard, but... I think I can finally beat the last boss!
いや〜最後までみっちり面白かったですが
Man, that was interesting all the way to the end.
…って第3形態だとぉぉぉ！
Wait, it has a third form?!
う〜ん、レトロゲームって良い意味で慈悲ないんだよね〜
Yeah, retro games have no mercy, in a good way.
うわあああああああ！！
Waaaaaah!!
Oh...
しんでしまうとはなさけない！
Death should not have been lamentable!
3 2 1 Q!
3, 2, 1, Go!
王！
King!
なに？
What?
HELP!
何事じゃ
What is it?
ひぃ、ひぃ、姫がさらわれましたぁ
H-H-Help, the princess has been kidnapped!
勇者は？
Where is the hero?
いません
There isn't one.
うーん、そうだ！
Hmm... I know!
ええ？
What?
かくなる上はお前が勇者だ
In that case, you are the hero!
設定崩壊！
The setting's ruined!
さあ、その宝箱の中身とこの情けないの金で旅立って
Now, take the contents of this chest and this pathetic gold and go.
仲間を探して化けもん倒して…
Find some allies, defeat some monsters...
適当じゃねーか
That's way too vague!
とにかく困ったら町の人々に話しかけようぜ
Anyway, if you're stuck, just talk to the townspeople.
ボスとか全然倒せる倒せる
You can definitely beat the bosses, no problem.
マ・ジ・で！
Seriously?!
いばっていばっていばって当然
Of course you should be boastful.
だって実際に一番えらいから！
Because I'm actually the most important one!
人事みたいに言ってくれるぜ まったくもって上から目線すぎんよ
Easy for you to say! You're being way too condescending.
経験値 経験値 経験値積んで
Exp, exp, pile up those experience points.
もっと強靭な仲間探し給え
Go find some stronger allies.
てゆうか私は一兵卒です 有給休暇がデリート！デリート！
I'm just a lowly soldier! My paid leave is being deleted! Deleted!
そなたがラスボスを倒してくる日を楽しみにまっておるぞい！
I look forward to the day you defeat the final boss!
世界平和を取り戻す為
To restore world peace,
お国の平和を守る為
to protect the peace of the land.
後ろで指揮をとりましょう
I'll take command from the back
その多の経験値を伝えましょう
I'll pass on those extra experience points
あなたの為に 世界の為に
For your sake, for the world's sake
戦う僕らの愛国心
Our fighting patriotism
仲間も死んで絶体絶命寸前
Comrades dead, on the brink of desperation
やっぱりレベルが足りねえ
As I thought, our level's not high enough
あなたのパーティーは全滅しました。
Your party has been wiped out.
おお、神様よ！
Oh, God!
アーメン
Amen
おお！しんでしまうとはなさけない！
Oh! What a shame to have died!
さすればそなたにもう一度 きかいをあたえよう
I shall give you another chance
王様っ
My King!
なんですか
Yes?
王様っ
My King!
もう...もう無理です
I can't... I can't go on anymore
なんですとおお！
What did you say?!
弱音を吐くとはもっと情けない！
To speak such weakness is even more shameful!
経済力、軍事力ともに申し分ない我が国は当然
Our nation, with perfect economic and military power
優秀な人材も潤沢
Also has an abundance of talented people
人望厚いね
You're very popular
ただ一つ慢性的な問題は国家元首の奔放さ
The only chronic problem is the leader's self-indulgence
よく言えば無垢 悪く言えば...
Innocent if you're nice, but otherwise...
O・BA・KA
STU-PID
正真正銘 全人類は戦闘民族 いわずもがな
Truly, all humanity is a warrior race, goes without saying
協調性や順応性が重要なんて
Claiming cooperation and adaptability are important?
浮世はクソゲー！
This world is a trash game!
次のレベルになるには
To reach the next level
あと1000ポイントの経験が
You need 1000 more experience points
さらにはもっと自己主張が必要じゃ
Furthermore, you need to assert yourself more
挫けるな OK?
Don't give up. OK?
テリッサ ボロッソ ダンシパロット
Telissa Borosso Danshiparotto
魔法使いも使いもんになってきたが
The wizard is finally becoming useful, but
余裕しゃくしゃく薄笑いで
With a calm and composed slight smile
ごたくばっかならべて癪に障るぜ
Spouting nothing but tedious talk, it's annoying
ホリット ホリット ホリット馬鹿
Hollit Hollit Hollit fool
僧侶はホリット馬鹿で馬鹿なの？
Is the monk just a Hollit fool?
王のアタシを眠らすなんて
To fall asleep while I, the King, am talking
アンタら一体何様？
Who do you think you are?
さては謀反か？
Is this a rebellion?
僕は勇者じゃありません。むしろ
I'm not the hero. Rather
王が勇者だと思いまーす！
I think the King is the hero!
世界平和を取り戻すため
To restore world peace
お国の平和を守るため
To protect the nation's peace
最前線に身を投じませ
Throw yourself onto the front lines
支持率アップは目に見えた！
A rise in approval ratings is clear!
権益のため お金のため
For interests, for money
戦う王様 何を見る
Fighting King, what do you see?
近衛も瀕死 絶体絶命寸前
The Guard is dying, on the brink of desperation
しんでしまうとはなさけなあああああい！
What a shame to have dieeeeeed!
世界平和を取り戻すため
To restore world peace
あなたの笑顔を守るため
To protect your smile
魔王軍関連情報を
Information related to the Demon King's army
命からがらにかき集め
Gathering it for dear life
今日も今日とて鎮座している
Sitting enthroned again today
まことの勇者を待っている
Waiting for the true hero
他力本願ではありません
It's not about relying on others
わしらやつらにゃかなわねぇ...
We're just no match for them...
フブにゃ～♡
Fubu-nya~♡
今日も可愛いねぇ～♡
You're cute today too~♡
早く僕の妹にならないかなぁ～～
I wonder when you'll become my little sister~~
ならないよ！！
I won't!!
なんで白上のことそんなに妹にしたいの？
Why do you want to make Shirakami your sister so much?
え～？言われてみればなんでだろう？
Eh~? Now that you mention it, I wonder why?
可愛いからでしょ？ん～？
Because you're cute, right? Hmm~?
可愛いからでしょ？
Because you're cute, right?
可愛いからばっかりじゃん！もう！
You keep saying "because I'm cute"! Jeez!
え～～、お姉ちゃんわかんないなぁ～～
Ehh, big sister doesn't understand~~
まったく...お姉ちゃんは仕方ないなぁ...
Goodness... you're a hopeless big sister...
って、あ！
Wait, ah!
フブにゃ～～～！！！！♡♡♡♡
Fubu-nyaaaaa!!!!♡♡♡♡
My sister I love you
My angel many many care
For you know what I need
聞いて 聞いて 私お姉ちゃんだよ
Listen, listen, I'm your big sister
遊ば 遊ば あなたまだ喋れないのね？
Play, play, you still can't talk yet, can you?
お下がり普通は嫌でしょ？
Hand-me-downs are usually disliked, right?
むしろ喜んで着てる
Actually, I'm wearing them happily
完璧を演じなくちゃ
I must act perfectly
理想のお姉ちゃんだもん
Since I'm the ideal big sister
弱さを見せないことが
Not showing any weakness
逆に弱点なんです
Is actually my weakness
平等にチャンスはあるから
Because everyone has an equal chance
負けるな私！
Don't lose, me!
あなたの夢は右で
Your dream is on the right
私の夢は左
And my dream is on the left
ゆらゆらと迷っても
Even if we sway and get lost
諦めない性格よ
We have personalities that don't give up
泣きたい時は泣いて
When you want to cry, cry
笑いたい時は笑って
When you want to laugh, laugh
疲れたら休みましょ
If you're tired, let's take a break
困ったら相談乗るから
If you're in trouble, I'll give you advice
理由があるとするならば
If there's a reason
あなたは私の天使
It's because you are my angel
My little sister I love you
My little angel Bell Bell Kyu
Yeah, yeah, you know what I mean. Hoo!
そっぽ向かれて
You turn away from me
話すらできない
And we can't even talk
心配しすぎ
Worrying too much
話せないことだってある
There are things I just can't talk about
私は私でヤバイ
I'm crazy in my own way
手抜きは絶対ＮＧ
Cutting corners is absolutely NG
完璧を演じなくちゃ
I have to act perfectly
理想のお姉ちゃんだもん
Because I'm the ideal big sister
レベル上げ得意な方で
I'm good at leveling up
努力は惜しまない
I won't hold back my efforts
神様は必ず見てるよ
God is always watching
頑張っちゃう
I'll do my best
作った笑顔じゃない
It's not a fake smile
あなたのホントが好き
I like the real you
イライラが溜まったら
When frustration builds up
甘いもの食べちゃおう
Let's eat something sweet
認めたくない時ほど認めて
Accept it more when you don't want to
悔しい時は眠って
Sleep when you feel frustrated
雨の日は羽休み
Rest your wings on rainy days
濡れてたら拭いてあげるから
If you're wet, I'll wipe you dry
理由があるとすれば
If there is a reason
あなたは私の
You are my...
そんな表情するんだね
You make such an expression
初めて見た可愛いよ
It's the first time I've seen it, you're cute
自慢だから自信持って
I'm proud of you, so have confidence
見ておいでよ世界を
Go and see the world
あの子はいつも私の後ろをくっついて歩いていて
That girl always used to walk right behind me
いつのまにか一人で自分の夢に向かって突き進んでいて
And before I knew it, she was pushing forward towards her own dream all by herself
えっと、みんなも応援してあげてください！
Um, please everyone, give her your support too!
My little angel I love you せーの
My little angel I love you, ready, go
I love you
My little angel I love you せーの
My little angel I love you, ready, go
I love you
陰口なんて気にしてる場合じゃないでしょ
This is no time to be worrying about gossip
平等にチャンスはあるから負けるな私！
Everyone has an equal chance, so don't lose, me!
あなたの描く夢
The dream you draw
私の描く夢
The dream I draw
叶えよう約束ね
Let's make them come true, it's a promise
小指を重ねよう
Let's link our pinkies
あなたの夢は右で
Your dream is on the right
私の夢は左
My dream is on the left
ゆらゆらと迷っても
Even if we waver and get lost
どこかできっと繋がる
We'll surely connect somewhere
泣きたい時は泣いて
Cry when you want to cry
笑いたい時は笑って
Laugh when you want to laugh
疲れたら休みましょう
Let's rest when we're tired
困ったら相談乗るから
I'll listen if you're in trouble
理由があるとすれば
If there is a reason
あなたは私の天使
You are my angel
My little sister I love you
My little angel Bell Bell Kyu
Do you know what I mean. Hoo!
目指せよ快眠 勝ち取れ安眠
Aim for good sleep, win restful sleep
いざ夢の世界へ
Now, to the world of dreams
理想の眠りを求めて
Seeking the ideal slumber
さぁ始めよう おやすみ
Now let's begin, good night
ノンレム睡眠 レム睡眠
Non-REM sleep, REM sleep
私は囚われの姫
I am a captive princess
魔王の城の中で
Inside the Demon King's castle
独り閉じ込められては
Locked up all alone
毎日ひたすら眠っています
I sleep intently every single day
今宵も布団に入り
Tonight as well, I get into my futon
スヤスヤリスト生活
Living a peaceful sleeper's life
枕も シーツも
The pillow, the sheets
硬くて眠れない
They're too hard, I can't sleep
「君を寝具にしてやろうか」
'Shall I turn you into bedding?'
目指せよ快眠 勝ち取れ安眠
Aim for good sleep, win restful sleep
いざ夢の世界へ
Now, to the world of dreams
ふかふかの枕手に入れて
I'll get a soft, fluffy pillow
この疲れ癒したい
I want to heal this fatigue
恐れず前進 ほぐせよ全身
Move forward without fear, relax your whole body
まぶたを閉じたなら
Once you've closed your eyelids
すべすべのシーツの上で
On top of the smooth sheets
さぁ始めよう おやすみ
Now let's begin, good night
ノンレム睡眠 レム睡眠
Non-REM sleep, REM sleep
私は囚われの姫
I am a captive princess
悲鳴が響く夜に
On the night when screams echo
一人で檻を抜け出し
I sneak out of the cage alone
今日もお散歩へと行ってきます
And go out for a stroll today too
幾多の試練を越えて
Overcoming many trials
新たな寝具のもとへ
To a new set of bedding
おやすまくまで 猛毒で
Good night, with a deadly poison
死んでも眠りたい
I want to sleep even if I die
城ごとシングにしてやろうか
Shall I turn the whole castle into a bed?
掴めよ快眠
Seize that pleasant sleep
憑かれて安眠
Rest in a possessed slumber
いざ夢の向こうへ
Now, towards the other side of dreams
ハイテクセ目覚まし手に入れて
Get a high-tech alarm clock
気持ちよく目覚めたい
I want to wake up feeling good
まだまだ前進
Still moving forward
華麗に変身
Transforming splendidly
ご飯を食べたなら
After you've eaten your meal
最高のベッドにダイブして
Dive into the best bed
さぁ
Now
始めよう おやすみ
Let's begin, good night
明日はもっと 今日よりずっと
Tomorrow, even more than today
いい夢見れるかな
I wonder if I can have a good dream
フワフワの羽に包まれて
Wrapped in fluffy feathers
心ゆくまで眠りたい
I want to sleep to my heart's content
目指せよ快眠
Aim for pleasant sleep
勝ち取れ安眠
Win that peaceful rest
いざ夢の世界へ
Now, into the world of dreams
最高の眠りを求めて
In search of the best sleep
さぁ
Now
始めよう おやすみ
Let's begin, good night
もう
Just
あと5分 おやすみ
5 more minutes, good night
ノンレム睡眠 レム睡眠
Non-REM sleep, REM sleep
すやあ
Zzz...
うーむ、このマスコット可愛いな...
Hmm, this mascot is cute...
へー、野球かあ...
Oh, baseball...
もしかしたら球場にいるかもだよ！
Maybe they're at the stadium!
行ってみる？
Want to go see?
え！行ってみたい行ってみたい！
Eh! I want to go! I want to go!
チケットとってみるよ！
I'll try to get tickets!
何日空いてる？
Which days are you free?
ミ、ミオちゃん...
Mi, Mio-chan...
きゅん
*heart throb*
試合観戦中...
Watching the game...
うわあああミオちゃん
Uwaaaa Mio-chan
ここを押さえたら勝ちってコト！？
does this mean if we hold them here, we win!?
そうだよそうだよー！
That's right, that's right!
こんな激熱な試合見れるなんてー！
To think we'd see such an intense game!
...ってこれって
...And this is...
ホームランだよ！
It's a home run!
おかゆホームランだよ！
Okayu, it's a home run!
す、すごい...
Wow...
野球すっげーーー！！！
Baseball is amazing!!!
青のすみか
作詞・作曲: Tatsuya Kitani
Ao no Sumika
Lyrics/Composition: Tatsuya Kitani
どこまでも続くような青の季節は
The blue season that seems to go on forever
四つ並ぶ眼の前を遮るものは何もない
Nothing blocks our view as the four of us stand in line
アスファルト
Asphalt
蝉時雨を反射して
reflecting the chorus of cicadas
君という沈黙が聞こえなくなる
The silence called "you" becomes inaudible
この日々が色褪せる
Even if these days fade
僕と違う君の匂いを知ってしまっても
Even if I learn your scent which is different from mine
置き忘れてきた永遠の底に
At the bottom of the eternity we left behind
今でも青が棲んでいる
Even now the blue resides
今でも青は澄んでいる
Even now the blue is clear
どんな祈りも言葉も
No matter the prayer or words
近づけるのに届かなかった
Though we got close, they didn't reach
まるで静かな恋のような
Like a quiet love
頬を伝った夏のような色の中
In colors like a summer that trickled down our cheeks
君を呪う言葉がずっと喉の奥に支えてる
The words to curse you have been stuck in the back of my throat
また会えるよねって
Saying, "We can meet again, right?"
声にならない声
A voiceless voice
昼下がり じめつく風の季節は
The season of damp winds in the early afternoon
思い馳せる まだ何者でもなかった僕らの肖像
I reminisce on our portraits when we were still nobodies
何もかも分かち合えたはずだった
We should have been able to share everything
あの日から少しずつ
From that day, little by little
君と僕がもっと呪い合っていく
You and I curse each other more
君の笑顔の奥の憂いを
The sorrow behind your smile...
見落としたこと悔やみ...
Regretting what I overlooked...
徒花と咲いていて
Blooming like a fruitless flower,
朽ちていく君に
and as you decay,
さようなら
farewell.
今でも青が棲んでいる
Blue still lives within me even now.
今でも青は澄んでいる
Blue is still clear even now.
どんな祈りも言葉も
No matter the prayer or the words,
近づけるのに届かなかった
they could get close, but never reach you.
まるで静かな恋のような
Just like a quiet love,
頬を伝った夏のような色の中
within a color like the summer that trickled down my cheek,
君を呪う言葉がずっと喉の奥に仕えてる
words that curse you have been stuck in the back of my throat.
「また会えるよね」って
"We'll meet again, right?"
声にならない声
A voice that couldn't become a sound.
無限に膨張する銀河の星の
Like the stars of a galaxy expanding infinitely,
粒のような指の隙間をこぼれた
they slipped through the cracks of my fingers like grains.
すっかり野球ひとりでも見に来るようになってしまったな…
I've completely gotten used to coming to watch baseball all by myself...
ご飯並んでるうちにスターティングメンバー発表されたぞ〜
The starting lineup was announced while I was waiting in line for food~
…って、え？スターマン？
...Wait, huh? Starman?
…（手招きする動作）
...(Beckoning motion)
え？え？
Huh? Huh?
スターマンがこっそり僕について来いって言ってる…
Starman is secretly telling me to follow him...
どういうこと〜〜〜〜〜〜〜！？！？！？
What does this mean~~~~~~~!?!?!?!
ライトから〜 レフトまで〜
From right field~ to left field~
ヨコハマ ジャンジャン盛り上がって行こうジャン！
Yokohama, let's get more and more pumped up!
好きです！！Baseball！
I love it!! Baseball!
打って行こう！
Let's hit it!
打って 打って 打って 打って 打ってカットバシテ！
Hit it, hit it, hit it, hit it, hit it, knock it out of the park!
宇宙に飛んでけ星になれ
Fly into space and become a star.
ガッチリガッチリガッチリガッチリ守ってキャッチ
Firmly, firmly, firmly, firmly defend and catch.
ガッチリガッチリ愛してはなさない❤️
Firmly, firmly, love and never let go❤️
好きです！！Baseball！
I love it!! Baseball!
ヨコジャン ハマジャン 燃え燃えジャン
Yokojan, Hamajan, burning hot-jan.
目指すはあの星 ジャン ジャン JUMP！
Aim for that star, jan jan JUMP!
ヨコジャン ハマジャン イケイケジャン
Yokojan, Hamajan, go-go-jan.
ドキドキウキウキ Baseball！
Heart-pounding, exciting Baseball!
ニッポンの元気だ横浜ジャン！
It's Japan's energy, Yokohama-jan!
みんなの夢のせ ジャン ジャン ジャン
Carrying everyone's dreams, jan jan jan.
スーパープレーで燃え燃えジャン！
Burning hot with super plays-jan!
汗も涙も星になれ
Let sweat and tears become stars.
さぁみんな両手を合わせてハッピースター☆ダンス
Now everyone, put your hands together for the Happy Star Dance.
まだまだ足りないよ！ほらほら！
It's still not enough! Come on, come on!
I LOVE ヨコハマ！
I LOVE Yokohama!
OK〜 まだまだ打って行こう！！
OK~ Let's keep hitting!!
打って 打って 打って 打って 打ってカットバシテ！
Hit it, hit it, hit it, hit it, hit it, knock it out of the park!
宇宙に飛んでけ星になれ
Fly into space and become a star.
ガッチリガッチリガッチリガッチリ守ってキャッチ
Firmly, firmly, firmly, firmly defend and catch.
ガッチリガッチリ愛してはなさない❤️
Firmly, firmly, love and never let go❤️
打って 打って 打って 打って 打ってカットバシテ！
Hit it, hit it, hit it, hit it, hit it, knock it out of the park!
宇宙に飛んでけ星になれ
Fly into space and become a star.
ガッチリガッチリガッチリガッチリ守ってキャッチ
Firmly, firmly, firmly, firmly defend and catch.
ガッチリガッチリ愛してはなさない❤️
Firmly, firmly, love and never let go❤️
好きです！！Baseball！
I love it!! Baseball!
1たす2たすスターマン♪
1 plus 2 plus Starman♪
しかくさんかくスターマン♪
Square, triangle, Starman♪
星型フェイスのスターマン
Star-shaped face Starman.
星型肉球スターマン
Star-shaped paw pads Starman.
か き く け こ こ キララちゃん♪
Ka-ki-ku-ke-ko-ko Kirara-chan♪
ハッピーラッキーキララちゃん♪
Happy lucky Kirara-chan♪
リズムにあわせてキララちゃん♪
To the rhythm, Kirara-chan♪
キラキラおどるよキララちゃん♪
Dancing sparkingly, Kirara-chan♪
さぁみんなで声あわせ
Now everyone, raise your voices together.
横浜の星
The star of Yokohama.
DeNAベイスターズ
DeNA BayStars.
すっ すっ すたすた すたスターマン♪
Su-su-suta-suta-suta Starman♪
きっ きっ きらきら きらキララちゃん♪
Ki-ki-kira-kira-kira Kirara-chan♪
みんなの夢をあつめる
Gathering everyone's dreams.
すっ すっ すたすた すたスターマン♪
Su-su-suta-suta-suta Starman♪
きっ きっ きらきら きらキララちゃん♪
Ki-ki-kira-kira-kira Kirara-chan♪
みんなの笑顔をつくるよ
We'll create everyone's smiles.
レッツゴー！
Let's go!
はい！ということで！
Alright! So!
横浜DeNAベイスターズのスターマンが特別ゲストで来てくれました！
DB.Starman from the Yokohama DeNA BayStars has joined us as a special guest!
可愛い！本物だよ！
He's so cute! It's the real one!
可愛すぎる！うわああ！
He's too cute! Wahhh!
お？あれ？
Oh? What's that?
わあ！「おかゆん誕生日おめでとう」だって！
Wow! It says "Okayun, Happy Birthday!"
おかゆん誕生日おめでとう！
Okayun, Happy Birthday!
ありがとうスターマン！
Thank you, Starman!
待って、あつい。あの、混乱してきちゃったけど...
Wait, I'm getting emotional. Um, I'm a bit overwhelmed, but...
一旦これだけ言わせて！
Let me just say this one thing!
ベイスターズ日本一本当におめでとう！
Congratulations to the BayStars on being #1 in Japan!
あははは、すごい喜んでいる！可愛い！
Hahaha, he's so happy! How cute!
いや、僕ね、スターマンに一目惚れして野球もね、好きになったんだよ！
You know, I fell in love with Starman at first sight, and that's how I started loving baseball!
ああ...もう胸いっぱいです。
Ah... my heart is so full.
あー可愛い、喜んでくれてる...
Ah, so cute, he's happy for me...
え、でもね、スターマンに謝らなきゃいけないことがあって...
Oh, but, there's something I have to apologize to Starman for...
あの...僕、最初スターマンのこと猫だと思ってて、僕の仲間なのかなって思ったんだけど...
Um... at first, I thought Starman was a cat and that we were the same kind, but...
あ、やばい、怒ってる怒ってる！
Ah, oh no, he's mad, he's mad!
ファンの人に「タヌキ」って言われて怒ってた時にやった背負い投げだ！
That's the judo throw he did when fans called him a "raccoon dog"!
すごい、キレ味やばい。生で見ると。
Wow, those moves are sharp. Seeing it in person.
え、スターマン、スターマン。あの、ちょっとね、お願いなんだけど...
Um, Starman, Starman. I have a little request...
よかったら一緒に、お写真撮ってもらえないかな？
If you don't mind, could we take a photo together?
あ！嬉しいー！
Ah! I'm so happy!
え、じゃあ、写真一緒に撮りたい。どうしよう、ポーズは...
Okay, then, let's take a photo. What pose should we do...
猫のポーズ、一緒に撮ってくれたりする？
Would you do a cat pose with me for the photo?
あ！ありがとう！じゃあ、ちょっとここら辺で...
Ah! Thank you! Okay, let's do it right around here...
スターマンもこっちちょっと来て。
Starman, come over here a bit.
えへへ、じゃあ、せーので猫のポーズするよ！
Ehehe, okay, let's do the cat pose on three!
せーの、にゃーん！
One, two, nyaan!
え、可愛い、可愛いけどさ、せっかくだからちょっとカメラ...
Aw, so cute. Since we're at it, let's get the camera...
カメラマンさん、こっちでもっと...あ、そうそう！
Mr. Cameraman, could you come closer... ah, yes, like that!
可愛い！可愛すぎる！
Cute! So cute!
にゃーん！
Nyaan!
スターマンはなんでこんなに可愛いんでしょうか。ありがとう、スターマン！
Why is Starman so adorable? Thank you, Starman!
あー、もう幸せすぎるな。もう何の悔いもございません。
Ah, I'm just too happy. I have no regrets left.
僕の人生には。お？
In my life. Oh?
なんか持ってる、スターマン。何それ？
You have something, Starman. What's that?
え！それ！
Eh! That's!
スターマンのサインじゃないの！？
Is that Starman's autograph!?
え、いいの？もらっちゃって！
Wait, can I really have it!?
え、ありがとうスターマン！いいのかな、いいのかな...あ！ありがとう！
Wow, thank you, Starman! Is this okay... ah! Thank you!
じゃーん！じゃじゃじゃーん！
Ta-da! Ta-da-da-da!
やばいよ、これ。最高すぎる。
This is amazing. It's too good.
あー、何回見ても、書いてあるサインが...ありがとう、スターマン！
Ah, no matter how much I look at this autograph... thank you, Starman!
大事にとっておくからね！よいしょ、よいしょっと。
I'll treasure this! Heave-ho.
あー、もうこれだけでも十分幸せなんだけど...
Ah, I'm happy enough just with this, but...
もしよかったら、もう一曲一緒に踊ってくれませんか？
If you'd like, would you dance one more song with me?
あ！OKいただきました！
Ah! He said yes!
え、何歌う？何歌う？スターマン？
Wait, what should we sing? What should we sing, Starman?
悩んでいる...。ん？
He's thinking... Hm?
あ！もぐもぐしてますね！可愛い！
Ah! You're chewing! So cute!
ということは、あの曲だね！
That means it's that song!
それじゃあ、一緒に歌おう！もぐもぐYUMMY！
Alright, let's sing it together! Mogu Mogu YUMMY!
森羅万象も 悪戦苦闘も
All of creation, all hard struggles
マヨネーズかけたら大体美味しくなる？
Will most things taste better if you put mayo on them?
君が泣いても お腹は空くよ
Even if you cry, you'll still get hungry
消化できなかったごめんごめん
I couldn't digest it, sorry, sorry
酸いも甘いも 勝手に食べて
The sour and the sweet, eating them as I please
ご迷惑おかゆしています
I'm causing trouble (Okayu-ing)
パクチー起きて 変な味のジュース
Coriander waking up, weird-tasting juice
心を無にして飲み込みます
Emptying my mind as I swallow it down
ああ混沌情報過多のレストランで
Ah, in this restaurant of chaotic information overload
嘘たちのメニューにお茶こぼして
Spilling tea over a menu full of lies
君とMOGU MOGU MOGU MOGU
With you, chewing, chewing, chewing, chewing
銃撃戦の真ん中で MOGU MOGU
In the middle of a gunfight, chewing, chewing
…の群れ
...crowd
満腹になる未来を願っているよ もぐもぐ
I'm praying for a future where I'm full, munch munch
もぐもぐ もぐもぐ
Munch munch, munch munch
世界が終わる前に
Before the world ends
もぐもぐやみぃ まじかみぃ
Munch munch yummy, truly godly
よむよむありのまんま
Chomp chomp just as I am
もぐもぐやみぃ まじかみぃ
Munch munch yummy, truly godly
この世を味わうんだ うまうま
I'm gonna taste this world, yummy yummy
理論武装のミルフィーユサンド
A theoretical Mille-feuille sandwich
匿名希望のオーロラソース
Aurora sauce wishing for anonymity
大雑把な味付け多めに見てよ
Forgive my sloppy seasoning
美味しくなったらオッケーオッケー
If it tastes good, it's okay, okay
良いも悪いもいっぱい食べて
Eat plenty of both good and bad things
汚れた口元拭いましょう
And wipe your messy mouth
おにぎり ピザ ケーキ 豪華なフルコース
Rice balls, pizza, cake, a luxurious full course
罠を疑い気がつきます
Suspicious of a trap, I realize
阿鼻叫喚のバイキングで
At the agonizing buffet
毒入りと絶品料理よりわけて
Separating the poison from the delicacies
君ともぐもぐ もぐもぐ
Munch munch munch munch with you
デスゲームの教室でもぐもぐ
Munching in the death game classroom
チミも御腹ペコの群れ
You're part of the hungry crowd too
仲の良い君と生き残れたらいいな
I hope I can survive with you, my good friend
もぐもぐ もぐもぐ
Munch munch, munch munch
数年後もこの場所でもぐもぐ
Munching at this place years later too
もぐもぐやみぃ まじかみぃ
Munch munch yummy, truly godly
今夜の晩御飯は
Tonight's dinner is...
もぐもぐやみぃ まじかみぃ
Munch munch yummy, truly godly
次はお前の番だ
Next is your turn
もぐもぐやみぃ まじかみぃ
Munch munch yummy, truly godly
よむよむありのまんま
Chomp chomp just as I am
もぐもぐやみぃ まじかみぃ
Munch munch yummy, truly godly
この世を味わうんだ うまうま
I'm gonna taste this world, yummy yummy
お疲れ様でした！
Thanks for your hard work!
はぁ〜
Whew~
みんなもゲストとして参加してくれてすごい嬉しかったしさ
I was so happy to have everyone join as guests.
スターマンがまさか僕の誕生日をお祝いしに来てくれるなんて
I never expected Starman to come and celebrate my birthday.
もう僕は満足で死にそうだよ
I'm so satisfied I could die.
ん？あ！そうでした
Hmm? Oh! That's right.
さて、ここでまず一つ目の告知です！
Now, here is the first announcement!
どうぞ！
Here it is!
特報
Special News
2ndアルバム 発売決定！！
2nd Album Release Decided!!
ぺるそにゃりすぺくと
PERSONA RESPECT
2025.5.14 2ndアルバム
2025.5.14 2nd Album
楽曲提供: DECO*27 / FLG4 / koyori / R Sound Design / TOOBOE / ピノキオピー / 稲葉曇 / 式浦躁吾 / 神山羊
Song Contributors: DECO*27 / FLG4 / koyori / R Sound Design / TOOBOE / PinocchioP / Inaba Kumori / Shikiura Sougo / Kamiyama Yoh
配信終了後より予約開始！！
Reservations start after the stream!!
あ、ティザームービーも終わってた
Ah, the teaser movie is over.
はい、僕のセカンドフルアルバム『ぺるそにゃりすぺくと』の発売が決定しましたー！
Yes, my second full album 'PERSONA RESPECT' is officially confirmed for release!
やったー！
Yay!
2024年2月にリリースされたピノキオピーさん書き下ろしの『ネコカブリーナ』に加えて
In addition to 'Nekokaburina' written by PinocchioP and released in February 2024...
8曲の新曲をこのアルバムのために制作した全9曲入りです
...it features 8 new songs produced for this album, for a total of 9 tracks.
究極の9曲！
The ultimate 9 songs!
DECO*27さん、FLG4さん、koyoriさん
DECO*27, FLG4, koyori...
R Sound Designさん、TOOBOEさん
R Sound Design, TOOBOE...
稲葉曇さん、式浦躁吾さん
Inaba Kumori, Shikiura Sougo...
神山羊さん
...and Kamiyama Yoh.
今回新曲の制作にはとっても豪華な作家さんに参加していただきました
We had a truly amazing lineup of creators participate in the production of the new songs this time.
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
今日はアルバムから先行シングルを1曲披露したいと思います
Today, I'd like to perform one of the pre-release singles from the album.
それでは聴いてください
Please have a listen.
行くぞ！
Here we go!
キスだけでいいからね
Just a kiss is fine
あなたはまだ私の心を知らない
You still don't know my heart
ため息混じりでもその気になっちゃう それが嫌
Even with a sigh mixed in, I find myself feeling that way, and I hate it
見え透いた優しさで気が向いたら思い出して
If you feel like it with your transparent kindness, please remember
残されるくらいなら騙されるほうがいいわ
If I'm to be left behind, I'd rather be deceived
キスだけでいいからね
Just a kiss is enough
それだけで私はいいの
That's all I need
交差するいつまでもこのままで
Crossing forever as we are
繋いでる時間だけ居なくなっていいからね
It's okay if you disappear during the time we're connected
私はまだあなたの言葉が聴きたい
I still want to hear your words
何気ないことでもまた気になっちゃう だから嫌
Even trivial things start to bother me again, that's why I hate it
行き過ぎた優しさで気がついたら虚しくなる
If I notice with your excessive kindness, I start to feel empty
嘘ついて傷だらけそんなことどうでもいいわ
Lying and full of wounds, I don't care about any of that
キスだけでいいからね
Just a kiss is enough
それだけで私はいいの
That's all I need
交差するいつまでもこのままで
Crossing forever as we are
繋いでる時間だけ二人になって
Becoming two just during the time we're connected
キスだけでいいからね
Just a kiss is enough
今だけでいいからね
Just for now is enough
本当は痛くなってしまうけど
To tell the truth, it starts to hurt, but
まだこのままでいいからね
I'm okay with staying like this for now
いいからね
It's okay
いやあ、ゴンドラ動いたんですけど。
Wow, the gondola moved!
はい、ということで、セカンドアルバムから新曲、「キスだけでいいからね」でした。
Yes, so that was "Kiss Dake de Ii kara ne,"
a new song from my second album.
大人っぽかったかな？ ひひひひ。
Was it mature enough? Hee hee hee.
この曲は神山羊さんに制作していただきました。ありがとうございます。
This song was produced by Yoh Kamiyama-san. Thank you very much.
前回書き下ろしていただいた琥珀糖とはね、
Compared to "Kohakuto" which he wrote for me before,
また違う雰囲気のサウンドで、もう素敵だなと思いました。
it has a different atmosphere, and I thought it was just wonderful.
僕もね、このお披露目する時に、こんな綺麗な歌僕に歌いこなせるのかな、
I also felt, "Can I really pull off singing such a beautiful song?"
みたいな気持ちあったんですけど、
when I was about to reveal it,
みんな喜んでくれたよね？
but everyone enjoyed it, right?
はい、この後、配信終了後にMVの公開、
Yes, the MV will be released after this stream ends,
24時から先行配信もあるので、楽しみにしてて下さいね。
and advanced distribution starts at 24:00, so please look forward to it.
さらに、こちらの「キスだけでいいからね」が、
Furthermore, this song "Kiss Dake de Ii kara ne" will be
オリジナルゲーム「おかゆにうむ」のエンディングテーマになります！
the ending theme for my original game "Okayunium"!
クリアしないと聴けないよ。
You can't hear it unless you clear the game.
いよいよ！ 2025年2月27日リリース！！
Finally! Release on February 27, 2025!!
ついに、来週27日、木曜日に発売です。あっという間だったなあ。
Finally, it's being released next Thursday, the 27th. It went by so fast.
いやあ、ついにね、発売しちゃいます、ということで。
Wow, it's finally being released.
なんか自分のことなのに、自分のことじゃないような、
It's about me, but I've felt like it's not really about me,
ずっとそんな気持ちだったんですが、
all this time,
まあ、発売楽しみです。
well, I'm looking forward to the release.
あ、予約できてないよーって人は、
Ah, for those who haven't pre-ordered yet,
各販売店さんと、
at various retailers,
ダウンロード版もあるので、
there's also a download version,
チェックしてみてねー。
so please check it out.
合わせてアニメイトさんで、発売記念抽選会が実施予定なので、
Also, a release commemorative lottery is planned at Animate,
詳細は公式ホームページと、エンターグラムさんの公式Xを、要チェックです！
so be sure to check the official website and Entergram's official X for details!
そして、この『イッスだけでいいから』が収録されるアルバムなのですが、
And regarding the album that includes "Issu Dake de Ii kara",
今回初めて、ホロライブオフィシャルショップ限定販売の、
we're releasing a limited-quantity edition exclusively on the
数量限定版もリリースします！
Hololive Official Shop for the first time!
こちらの2枚のアルバムキービジュアルが、飾って楽しめる、
It's a special box that lets you display and enjoy
スペシャルボックス仕様となっております！
these two album key visuals!
ボックスの中には、アルバムデザインのアクリルスタンド、トールサイズケース、
Inside the box are an acrylic stand with the album design, a tall-size case,
さらに、ホロライブオフィシャルカードゲームのおかゆカードも収録されております！
and even an Okayu card from the Hololive Official Card Game is included!
コナキナコ先生、石原立也先生、描き下ろしのイラストを、両方飾って楽しめる、
You can display and enjoy both the newly drawn illustrations by Konakinako-sensei and Ishihara Tatsuya-sensei.
数量限定版の購入は、先着順となっておりますので、お見逃しなく！
The limited-quantity edition is available on a first-come, first-served basis, so don't miss out!
おにぎりゃー先着順とかあんまり慣れてなさそうで、心配なんですけど、大丈夫おにぎりゃー？
I'm a bit worried since Onigiri-ya might not be used to first-come, first-served. You guys okay?
続きまして、全国のCDショップで買える通常版には、店舗別特典が付きます！
Moving on, the regular edition available at CD shops nationwide comes with store-specific benefits!
お店ごとに、たくさん種類があるので、ぜひチェックしてみてくださーい。
There are many types for each store, so please check them out.
セカンドアルバム『PERSONA RESPECT』の発売まで、いろんな情報解禁があると思いますので、それぞれ楽しみにしていてね。えへへ。
I think there will be various information reveals leading up to the release of the 2nd album "PERSONA RESPECT", so look forward to each of them. Hehe.
え、え、何？まだあるの？
Eh, eh, what? There's more?
特報
Special News
猫又おかゆ Okayu Ch.
Nekomata Okayu Okayu Ch.
2025.5.28
ぴあアリーナMM
Pia Arena MM
2nd Live 開催決定
2nd Live confirmed
PERSONA RESPECT
coming soon
えー！えーー！！セカンドライブ、決定ーー！！
Eh! Eeh!! 2nd Live confirmed!!
うわぁぁぁぁ！うにゃぁ！あ、うにゃぁは違うか。
Uwaaaaa! Unyaaa! Ah, "unya" is wrong.
え、なんか会場大きかったよね？ええー！？
Eh, the venue looked big, didn't it? Eeh!?
あ、待って、カンペ出てる。
Ah, wait, there's a cue card.
チケットとか、ライブグッズの詳細は、後日発表するので、楽しみにしててね。
Details about tickets and live goods will be announced later, so look forward to it.
ちなみに、アルバムとライブ共通のハッシュタグは、こちらです！
By the way, the common hashtag for the album and the live is this one!
#おかゆセカンド
#OkayuSecond
え、ぜひたくさん呟いてくださいねー、だって。えー、もうなんかもうマジ？
It says, "Please tweet a lot." Eh, I'm like... seriously?
ほらみんな、僕のライブ来てくれる...来てくれるのかな？
Look everyone, will you come to my live... will you come?
不安だよー、不安だよー。でも楽しみだよー。あはははは。
I'm anxious, I'm anxious. But I'm excited too. Ahahaha.
情緒イカれちまった。
My emotions are all over the place.
えっと、次が、最後の告知です！
Umm, the next one is the final announcement!
ドドン！『猫又おかゆ、誕生日記念グッズ』が出ます！！
Bada-bing! "Nekomata Okayu Birthday Commemorative Goods" are coming out!!
ドンドンパフパフ！
Don don puff puff!
それじゃあ、一つずつ、商品見ていきましょう。
Well then, let's look at the products one by one.
まずは、こちら！ドドン！『ごろごろラバーマット』！
First, this one! Bada-bing! The "Gorogoro Rubber Mat"!
イラストは、僕のママ、神岡ちろる先生に描き下ろしていただきました。
The illustration was newly drawn by my "mama", Kamioka Chirol-sensei.
ラバーマットはね、結構前にグッズで出したことあったんだけど、
I've released a rubber mat as merch quite a while ago,
ま、そろそろね、使い続けてる人のラバーマットも、もしかしたら、そろそろ買い替え時かなーってなってたり、
well, for those who've been using it, it might be time for a replacement,
それこそ当時は、おかゆのこと知らなかったーっていう人がさ、買えてなかったりする時期になってきたのかなーと思って、
or for people who didn't know about Okayu back then and couldn't buy it, I thought it's about time,
ラバーマット、出してみました.可愛いでしょ？僕めちゃゴロゴロしてんの。えへへ。
so I decided to release a rubber mat. Cute, right? I'm lounging around so much. Hehe.
もう最近はね、ホロカも...
And lately, HoloCa too...
めちゃめちゃみんなやってるって聞きますし、
I hear a lot of people doing it,
そういうのに使ったりとか
so you can use it for things like that,
パソコンの前に置いて使うのもとってもいいと思います！
I think it's also really good to put it in front of your computer!
続きましてこちら！
Moving on to the next one!
ライブ映えもばっちり おかゆＴシャツ
Perfect for looking great at live events! Okayu T-shirt
Ｔシャツもね、すごい前に出したことあったけど、
I've released T-shirts before, a long time ago,
ま、ライブに来てくんだったらこのＴシャツマジで神じゃない？
But if you're coming to a live show, isn't this T-shirt just perfect?
ということで、選ばせていただけました。
So, I decided on this one.
描き下ろしはシズさんです！
The illustration is by Shizu-san!
シズ先生ありがとうございます！
Thank you, Shizu-sensei!
めっちゃかっこいいですよー！
It's really cool!
ま、こんなかっこいい猫又おかゆ見れるのは
Well, this might be the only place you can see
このＴシャツだけかもしれないということで、ぜひ皆さんこれを着てね、
such a cool Nekomata Okayu, so everyone, please wear this,
ライブとかいろんなところ遊びに行ってください。
and go to live shows and various other places.
普段使いもしやすいよね！
It's also easy to wear every day!
はい！続いてはこちら！
Yes! Next is this!
気づいた？実はおかゆのズボンモチーフリュック
Did you notice? It's actually a backpack based on Okayu's pants
いや、これは僕のね、通常衣装の
Well, this backpack has a design
ズボンをモチーフにしたデザインのリュックとなっております。
inspired by my standard outfit's pants.
フロントポケットにはね、ホロフレが２個、２体、２匹入る設計となっております。
The front pocket is designed to fit two Holo-Friends—two units, two of them.
チャームとかもさ、かっちり猫で可愛いでしょ？
Even the charm is a cute cat, isn't it?
これはマジでね、運営さんにお願いして細部までこだわりました。
I really asked the staff and we paid attention to every detail.
横についてるタグみたいなやつは、僕のね、通常衣装の靴を、
The tag-like thing on the side is inspired by my
衣装じゃなくって、あれなんです。イメージしたものになっているんですね。
standard outfit's shoes, rather than the outfit itself.
ま、去年の生誕ライブでは僕のここに、おにぎりが書いてるパーカーを出したから、
Well, for last year's birthday live, I released a hoodie with an onigiri on it,
ま、それとセットでね、こうやってリュックを背負ったら、
so if you wear this backpack as a set with that...
なんか遠目に見ると横になってるおかゆみたいに見えるんじゃないかなって思ってます。
I think from a distance, it might look like Okayu lying on her side.
最近はね、ぬいぐるみをつれてライブに来てくれてる人が多いので、ぬいぐるみも入れられるデザインにしてみました！
Lately, many people bring plushies to live shows, so I chose a design that can hold plushies!
はい、続きましてこちら！
Yes, moving on to the next one!
保存しやすいチェキホルダー
Easy-to-store cheki holder
イラストはね、あの、僕がデザインさせていただきました。
As for the illustration, well, I designed it myself.
こちらは、ま、よく出したりするチェキが入れられるサイズとなっております。
This is a size that fits the cheki photos we often release.
それこそね、さっき発表があったリュックにつけて行くもよしだし、
You can attach it to the backpack I just announced,
ま、チェキホルダーとしてお部屋に飾ったりなんかしても絶対可愛いよね。
or you could display your cheki photos in your room—that would definitely be cute too.
映えを意識してオーロラ加工していただいております！
We added an aurora finish to make it look great!
ふぅー、息ちょっと整えて...
Phew, let me catch my breath for a second...
はい、続いてはこちら！
Yes, next is this!
フルセット購入特典
Full Set Purchase Bonus
今回もございました、フルセット特典。
We have a full set bonus this time as well.
直筆サイン入りチェキ風ブロマイドと特典ボイスがついてきます！
It comes with a hand-signed cheki-style bromide and a bonus voice track!
今回もね、無制限でやらせていただきますから、
Once again, we'll be doing this without a limit,
みんな急がなくて大丈夫です。ゆっくり買ってくれれば大丈夫なんです。
so there's no need to rush. You can take your time with your purchase.
はい、特典ボイスタイトルは『おかゆぬいぐるみとおでかけ編』。
The bonus voice title is 'Outing with Okayu Plushie.'
ぬいぐるみ視点の珍しいシチュエーションとなっております。
It's a rare situation from the plushie's perspective.
さっきのリュックにね、あの、２体入るよって言ったんで、
Since I mentioned earlier that two plushies fit in the backpack,
そのぬいぐるみかリュックの中にいるときは
this voice track imagines what kind of scenery they see
どういう景色を楽しんでて、どういう気持ちなのかなっていうのをイメージしたボイスとなっております。
and how they feel while they're inside the backpack.
ぜひおカヌイをリュックに入れて聞くと臨場感があって楽しめるボイスとなっております！
If you listen to it while putting O-ka-nui in your backpack, you'll really enjoy it!
続いてはこちら！
Next is this!
プロモカード
Promo Card
タレントプレミアムグッズのフルセット特典として、
As a bonus for the Talent Premium Goods full set,
ホロライブオフィシャルカードゲームで使用できるカードが１枚ついてきます！
you'll receive one card that can be used in the Hololive Official Card Game!
セットのみ、対象となります。
...only for those who purchased the full set.
特典につくのは、推しをアピールできるEカード、推しホロメンカードです。
Included as a bonus is an "Oshiholo-men Card,"
a special card that lets you show off your favorite member.
カードの詳細や遊び方については、ホームページにてご確認ください。
Please check the official website for more information
about the card and how to play.
カードは日本語版のみとなりますので、ご了承ください。
The card is only available in Japanese,
so please keep that in mind.
誕生日記念グッズは、僕のセカンドライブの日には、ちょっとごめんなさい、届かないんだけど...
The birthday goods might not reach you
in time for my second live... sorry about that...
今後のイベントでかっこいいTシャツ着たり、リュック背負ったりね、
But I'd be so happy if you could wear the cool t-shirt,
carry the backpack,
チェキ身につけたりで、推し活していただけると非常に嬉しいです。
or put on the cheki holder to support me at future events!
あ、おにぎり屋来てるなーって、一目で分かるのはね、めちゃめちゃ嬉しいんで。
Seeing at a glance that "Oh, an Onigiri-ya (fan) is here!"
makes me so happy.
ここまでさ、もうダッシュで来たから口の中よだれまみれなんだけど、今。
Whew... I've been running at full speed so far,
my mouth is full of saliva now.
あはは！こうやってるとみんなに飛ばしてるみたいになる、飛ばさないけどさ。
Haha! It looks like I'm spitting on everyone,
but I won't do that!
今回のね、誕生日ライブは、今までの僕の思い出をね、大事にしてるものを振り返りつつ...
For this birthday live, I looked back on the memories
I cherish from my past...
みんなへの感謝の気持ちも伝えられるように、いろいろライブの構成を考えてきました。
and I thought a lot about the structure so that
I could express my gratitude to everyone.
なので、エピソードパートはですね、実際にあった思い出を書き起こしてもらっています。
So, the episode parts are based on real memories
that were written out for me.
懐かしかったでしょ？
Wasn't it nostalgic?
特にね、ころさんと「もしも」してるところとかはさ、僕もすごい懐かしいーってなったわけよ。あはは！
Especially the part where I did a "What if?" with Korone-san...
I felt really nostalgic too. Haha!
これも全部全部、みんなの支えがあったおかげです。本当にありがとうございます。
All of this is thanks to everyone's support.
Thank you so much.
この場をお借りして、本当に本当にありがとう。
I want to take this opportunity to say thank you,
truly, thank you.
まだなんかさ、いろいろ伝えたいこともあるけど、そろそろバイバイの時間になってしまいました。
There's still so much I want to say,
but it's almost time to say goodbye.
まあ、いろいろまた話すのは、次の配信でになるかな。
I'll talk more in the next stream.
じゃあ、みんな、今日はここまで楽しんでくれてありがとう！
Alright, everyone, thank you for enjoying today with me!
せーの、バイバイ！
One, two... Bye-bye!
ちょっと臆病な僕が好き。
I like my slightly cowardly self.
強がってる 僕が好き。
I like my self that acts tough.
弱さを知ってる 君が好きだよ。
I like you, who knows what it's like to be weak.
1・2・3で飛び込め！
Jump in on the count of 1, 2, 3!
いつか描いた未来が
Because the future I once envisioned...
ボクのポケットにあるから
...is right here in my pocket.
いっせーので初めて
The very first time we together...
ためらうことなどナイ！
...there was no hesitation!
「そなたがラスボスを倒してくる日を楽しみにまっておるぞい」
"I'm looking forward to the day you defeat the final boss!"
世界平和を取り戻すぞ
We're going to take back world peace!